Our parents always told us that if we worked hard we would achieve good grades.
我们的父母总是告诉我们，如果我们努力学习，就会取得好成绩。
If you're studying at university that ultimately means passing your exams and getting a first-class degree.
如果你正在大学学习，这最终意味着要通过考试并获得一个一等学位。
Easier said than done!
说起来容易做起来难啊！
So if you're struggling to finish that final assignment or feel like your revision is getting nowhere, how can you believe that getting a top-notch qualification is doable?
所以，如果你在挣扎着完成最后一项作业，或者觉得你的复习毫无进展，你又怎么能相信获得一个顶尖的学历是切实可行的呢？
I can't claim to be an expert in this as the grade I achieved in my degree was a little lower than a first!
我不能自称是这方面的专家，因为我在学位课程中取得的成绩略低于一等！
But today, in the UK at least, there are encouraging signs that getting one is a bit more attainable.
但如今，至少在英国，有一些令人鼓舞的迹象表明，获得一等学位变得稍微更可实现了。
That's because the number of first-class degrees being awarded by UK universities is soaring, with firsts now more common than a 2:2.
这是因为英国大学授予的一等学位数量正在急剧增加，现在一等学位比2:2学位更为常见。
More than a quarter of students received a first in 2015 and 2016 at the UK's top universities, known as the Russell Group.
在被称为“罗素集团”的英国顶尖大学中，在2015年和2016年，超过四分之一的学生获得了一等学位。
Among specialist institutions, such as in the creative arts, proportions of firsts are thought to be even higher — such as 64% of students getting firsts at the Royal Academy of Music.
在一些专业院校，比如在创意艺术领域，获得一等学位的比例据认为更高——例如，在皇家音乐学院，64%的学生获得了一等学位。
Of course, not everyone thinks this is because of the hard graft that students are putting in.
当然，并不是每个人都认为这是因为学生们付出了辛勤的努力。
Critics say that universities are handing out higher grades to boost applications and having a first-class degree gives an advantage for future job opportunities — this all looks good on a university prospectus.
批评者们表示，大学在发放更高的分数以增加申请人数，而且拥有一个一等学位会在未来的就业机会中占据优势——这些在大学的招生简章上看起来都会很亮眼。
But there have also been arguments that rising degree grades reflect the improved A-level grades of those entering university and a more focused attention to studying.
但也有一些说法表示，学位成绩的提高反映了进入大学的学生在A-Level考试中成绩的提升，以及对学习更加专注。
But whatever the reason, we mustn‘t deny first-class graduates their hard-earned achievement and success.
但无论原因是什么，我们不能否认一等学位获得者们来之不易的成就和成功。
Many have made sacrifices along the way, such as 22 year old Khadijah Lewis, who got a first in history and sociology at Warwick University.
许多人在这个过程中都做出了牺牲，比如22岁的卡迪嘉·刘易斯，她在华威大学获得了历史和社会学专业的一等学位。
She told the BBC’s Newsbeat programme that her course was “tough” but says “Knowing that getting a first is more common than a 2:2 does make me feel like my first isn‘t as valid,” she explains, “but also I know that I worked very hard for it, so regardless of how easy or how hard people think it is, I still did it.”
她告诉英国广播公司的《新闻节拍》节目，她的课程“很难”，但她说：“知道获得一等学位比获得2:2学位更常见确实让我觉得我的一等学位没那么有价值，”她解释道，“但我也知道我为此付出了很大的努力，所以不管人们认为这是容易还是困难，我还是做到了。”
Another student, Sam Gibbins, who got a first in software engineering at Cardiff Metropolitan University said he spent “a lot of nights in the library”.
另一名学生，在卡迪夫城市大学获得软件工程专业一等学位的山姆·吉宾斯说，他“在图书馆度过了很多个夜晚”。
But even though he did well, he says going to university is not just about the grades, he says “You develop so much going to university, and meet so many people, you’re able to understand yourself much better.”
但即使他成绩优异，他说上大学不仅仅是为了成绩，他说：“上大学让你成长了很多，还能结识很多人，你能够更好地了解自己。”
Some wise words; it sounds as though he studied at the university of life!
真是些明智的话；听起来他好像是在生活这所大学里学习过！